

# Henrik Korsgaard

PhD, Software Developer and Interaction Designer Hjortshøj, Denmark +45 22377114 henrikkorsgaard.dk

korsgaard@protonmail.com

#### **Profile**

I believe that developing good software begins with understanding the work and ambitions of the people who use it. Their expectations and experiences dictate how inventive and creative we have to be. I thrive in close collaboration with specialists and favour agile approaches to software development. My ambition is to develop tools and solutions that help people be the best at what they do.

### **Work Experience**

### Postdoc at Computer Science, Aarhus University [2017 - current]

This role span two main projects at the intersection of data science and human-computer interaction. I combined traditional academic research with development of experimental prototypes and research tools for cross-device interaction, data mining and visual analytics. Tasks and responsibilities include:

- Software design and development
- Data management and GDPR compliance
- Data analysis and visualisation
- Qualitative research
- Dissemination and publication
- Supervision and teaching

#### **Example technologies**

JavaScript, HTML/CSS, NodeJS, Golang, Python, MySQL, SQLite, oDATA, CKAN, pxWeb, Google API, Raspberry PI, NodeJS, D3.js, Electron.js, Github

### PhD at Computer Science, Aarhus University [2013 - 2017]

My PhD work focused on human-computer interaction from a place- and community centric perspective. The research included developing proof-of-concept prototypes for co-located cross-device interaction and proximity-based IoT infrastructure. Tasks and responsibilities included:

- Research and project development
- Software design and development
- Qualitative research
- Dissemination and publication
- Teaching

#### **Example technologies**

JavaScript, HTML/CSS, NodeJS, Golang, Java, SQLite, MongoDB, CKAN, Raspberry PI, PCAP, Dnsmasq, Nginx, Github

### Project assistant AU Smart Cities [2011 - 2013]

As a project assistant in AU Smart Cities, my role included project management and participation in local projects and contributing to ongoing EU projects and co-authoring new EU-project proposals. As part of the work I participated on behalf of AU Smart Cities in a local smart city partnership, Smart Aarhus, the RADICAL EU project, Danish Smart City network and the Aarhus open data work group. Tasks and responsibilities included:

- Proposal writing and project dissemination
- Feasibility studies and data modelling
- Consultancy on open data and smart city solutions

#### **Example technologies**

CoffeeScript, HTML/CSS, NodeJS, Objective-C, Java, PHP PostgreSQL/GIS, MongoDB, MySQL, CKAN, Github, SVN

#### Additional experience

2012	External Lecturer at Department of Aesthetics and Communication
2010 - 2012	Teaching Assistant at Department of Aesthetics and Communication
2011 - 2012	Internship at Center for Advanced Visualisation and Interaction
2006 – 2007	Cabinetmaker at Gorm Schierup.
2004 - 2006	Cabinetmaker at Brdr. Andersens Møbelsnedkeri.

References can be provided upon request.

### Education

2013 – 2016	PhD at Department of Computer Science, Aarhus University
2010 - 2013	MSc in Information Technology at Aarhus University
2007 – 2010	BA Information Studies and Multimedia at Aarhus University
2000 - 2004	Trained Cabinetmaker at Brdr. Andersens Møbelsnedkeri

### **Positions**

2017 – 2018	Member of Postdoc Committee at Computer Science, Aarhus University
2015 - 2017	Member of PhD Committee at Computer Science, Aarhus University
2015 – 2016	Organising Committee member at the 2016 Participatory Design Conference
2015	Proceedings Chair at the 5th Decennial Aarhus Conference
2013 - 2015	Judge for the 24 Hour OzCHI Design Challenge
2013 - 2014	Member of the Danish Smart City Network
2012 - 2013	Member of Aarhus Open Data work group
2011 - 2013	Member of the Smart Aarhus Secretariat

# Recognitions

- 2016 Honorable Mention paper award at Computer-Supported Cooperative Work
- 2016 Nominated for Faculty of Science & Technology talent award
- 2010 First price in OzCHI 24 Hour Design Challenge
- 2004 Bronze medal at Cabinetmaker apprenticeship

#### Invited talks

- 2017 "Making Place with Proximity Sensing", Digital Design and Inf. Studies, Aarhus University
- 2017 "A Space for Place in Interaction Design", Digital Design and Inf. Studies, Aarhus University
- 2017 "Peaking into the Facebook Machine", AU Talks, Aarhus Univeristy
- 2016 "A Space for Place in HCI", Participatory IT Centre, Aarhus University
- 2016 "Place-specific Computing", University of Colorado Boulder, US
- 2013 "Smart Aarhus A Danish Smart City", International Press Visit Aarhus
- 2013 "Smart Aarhus A Danish Smart City", Carbon20/Gate21 Seminar
- 2013 "Prototyping the Smart City", Intel European Research & Innovation Conference

# **Funding applications**

Co-author on RADICAL (CIP-ICT-PSP)

Co-author on Organicity (Horizon 2020 ICT-11a FIRE+)

Travel grant Augustinus Fonden

Travel grant Oticon Fonden

Funded: €5.5m

Funded: €7.2m

Funded: DKK 17.500

Funded: DKK 13.500

# **Teaching**

I have experience in teaching, supervising projects and developing courses on bacehlor's and master's level within the Computer Science and IT programme and Digital Design and Information Studies programme.

- 2019 Lecturer: IT-Product Design, IT BS
- 2018 Lecturer: User Experience, CS/IT MSc
- 2015 TA: Experimental System Development
- 2013 TA: IT Case project
- 2012 Lecturer: Advanced Interaction Design, Inf. Studies, MSc
- 2011 TA: Interaction Design, Inf. Studies, BA
- 2010 TA: Introduction to Programming and OO Modelling, Inf. Studies BA

### Selected Publications

Ida Larsen-Ledet and **Henrik Korsgaard**. 2019. Territorial Functioning in Collaborative Writing. Comput. Supported Coop. Work 28, 3-4 (June 2019), 391-433.

Nathalie Bressa, Kendra Wannamaker, **Henrik Korsgaard**, Wesley Willett, and Jo Vermeulen. 2019. Sketching and Ideation Activities for Situated Visualization Design. In Proceedings of the 2019 on Designing Interactive Systems Conference (DIS '19). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 173-185.

**Henrik Korsgaard**, Sarah-Kristin Thiel, Vanessa Thomas, and Titiana Ertiö. 2018. Working across boundaries in smart city research. In Proceedings of the 19th Annual International Conference on Digital Government Research (dg.o '18) ACM, New York, NY, USA, Article 39, 10 pages.

Carla Gröschel, Peter Dalsgaard, Clemens N. Klokmose, **Henrik Korsgaard**, Eva Eriksson, Raphaëlle Bats, Aurélien Tabard, Alix Ducros, and Sofia E. Serholt. 2018. PARTICIPATE: Capturing Knowledge in Public Library Activities. In Extended Abstracts of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI EA '18). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 6 pages.

**Henrik Korsgaard**. 2017. Toward Place-Centric Computing: Making Place With Technology Together. PhD dissertation. Department of Computer Science, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.

Jens Emil Grønbæk, **Henrik Korsgaard**, Marianne Graves Petersen, Morten Henriksen Birk, and Peter Gall Krogh. 2017. Proxemic Transitions: Designing Shape-Changing Furniture for Informal Meetings. In Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI '17). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 7029-7041.

**Henrik Korsgaard**, Clemens Nylandsted Klokmose, and Susanne Bødker. 2016. Computational Alternatives in Participatory Design: Putting the T back in Socio-Technical Research. In Proceedings of the 14th Participatory Design Conference (PDC '16), Vol. 1. ACM, New York, NY, USA, 71-79.

Susanne Bødker, **Henrik Korsgaard**, Peter Lyle, and Joanna Saad-Sulonen. 2016. Happenstance, Strategies and Tactics: Intrinsic Design in a Volunteer-based Community. In Proceedings of the 9th Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction (NordiCHI '16). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Article 10, 10 pages.

**Henrik Korsgaard** and Martin Brynskov. 2014. City bug report: urban prototyping as participatory process and practice. In Proceedings of the 2nd Media Architecture Biennale Conference: World Cities (MAB '14). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 21-29.

Brynskov, Martin, Juan Carlos Carvajal Bermúdez, Manu Fernández, Henrik Korsgaard, Ingrid Mulder, Katarzyna Piskorek, Lea Rekow, and Martijn de Waal. 2014. Urban Interaction Design: Towards City Making. Amsterdam, Netherlands.

**Henrik Korsgaard**. 2013. Digital Urban Development: Reconceptualising the Smart City as a Design Challenge from an Interaction Design Perspective. Master's thesis. Department of Aesthetics and Communication, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.

**Henrik Korsgaard**, Nicolai Brodersen Hansen, Ditte Basballe, Peter Dalsgaard, and Kim Halskov. 2012. Odenplan: a media façade design process. In Proceedings of the 4th Media Architecture Biennale Conference: Participation (MAB '12). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 23-32.

Wiltschnig, S., **Korsgaard H.**, & Dalsgaard, P. (2011). Mapping Insights in Creative Processes–Prototyping Integrative Research Designs for Design Research. In DESIRE-Creativity and Innovation in Design.

Full publication list and PDFs are available on henrikkorsgaard.dk